## MOHAMED HASSAN MAHGOUB MERGANI



GEOLOGIST-HYDROLOGIST

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

MOB: 053 209 7158

EMAIL: <u>hydro.mmergani@gmail.com</u> <u>engineer.mohamed92100@gmail.com</u>

#### Career Profile

I Have Good Hydrological - Geological Work Practice Knowland and Experience For More Than Five Years In Hydrological Studies Reports and Flood Protection Projects and Hydraulic Designing of Protection Facilities (Culverts and Channels ) and Storm Drainage Networks and Preparing Reports, I Have Been Involved in Small To Medium Flood Protection Projects, Good User of Engineering Softwares ARCMAP, WMS, GLOBAL MAPER, CIVIL 3D, SEWERGEMS, HYFRANPLUS, FLOWMASTER, CULVERTMASTER, Looking for a Challenging Position In The Hydrology Career Where I Can Apply My Knowledge And Experience For The Career Development And Organization As Well.

#### **Education**

Al- Neelain University - Faculty Of Petroleum And Minerals (Geology Department )

Bachelore Degree With Honors In Geology (2011 -2016 )

## **Experience Summary**

Geological Specialist | Abdelrahman Alghous Engineering Consultancy

Taif -Medina | Saudi Arabia

June 2022 - March 2023

#### **Duties**

Writing the Hydrological Reports And Approved Them From The Saudi Geological Survey (SGS) And Ministry of Municipal and Rural Affairs (MOMRA).

Geologist | Advanced Construction Technology Services (ACTS )
Tabuk -Neom | Saudi Arabia

January 2022 - March 2022

#### **Duties**

- ♦ Supervising of Rig activities & Ground Investigation Work.
- ♦ Monitoring of In Situ Testing and Reporting .
- ♦ Monitoring of on-going Work in The Field & Maintain Record of Inspection.
- ♦ Full Description of Materials and Creating Daft Borehole Logs.
- ♦ Preparing of Daily Report and Reporting.

# **Geologist | Miskifisho For Contracting And Investment Khartoum | Sudan**

March 2017 - April 2021

#### **Duties**

- ♦ Field visits To Sites for purpose of determining the streams of the rivers and all required hydrological properties and parameters for preparing hydrological study ( Curve Number, Land use, Soil Type) .
- ♦ Supervising The Drilling Work in The Site.
- ♦ Determine the Required Laboratory Tests and Send The Test Request To The Laboratory.
- ♦ Full Description Of Soil And Rock Samples.
- ♦ Writing The Final Reports (Hydrological Reports).

## Lab Technican (Trainee) | Central Laboratory For Soil And Mining Lab Khartoum | Sudan

March 2020 - April 2020

#### **Duties**

Short Training about Atomic Absorption Spectrometry (AAS) and XRF To Estimate The Analysis both Qualitative and Quantitative of Chemical Elements in the Samples By Using Flame and Furnace To Estimate the Chemical Elements in The Samples and Estimating the Quantity of the Elements.

## Training & Courses

#### **Field Training**

**Khartoum Area | Al -Neelain University** 

September 2011

3 Days Practical Field Education, Regional Geology, Sample Collection ,Sample Preparing for Geochemical Tests

#### Alsabaloga Area | Al -Neelain University

#### August 2012

15 Days Practical Field Education, Regional Geology, Sample Collection , sample Preparing For Geochemical Tests

#### Alsabaloga Area | Al -Neelain University

#### August 2013

15 Days Practical Field Education, Regional Geology, Detailed Geological Mapping.

#### Albutanah Area | Al -Neelain University

#### August 2014

21 Days Practical Field Education, Regional Geology, Structural Geology, Geophysical surveys for mineral exploration, Trench Mapping.

#### Abu hamad Station No (6) Area | Al -Neelain University

#### August 2015

21 Days Practical Field Education, Regional Geology, Structural Geology, Geophysical survey, Trench Mapping, Geotechnical and Geological core logging, Samples Description, Drilling supervising (diamond drilling &RC drilling), Geological Data entry, processing and interpretation.

#### Courses

- ♦ Hydrology Diploma
- ♦ Excel Skills For Business
- ♦ Write Professional Emails In English
- ♦ Introduction To Petroleum Engineering
- ♦ Crush Course In Gold Processing
- ♦ Crisis And Disaster Management
- ♦ Seismic Tomogrphy. Look Inside The Eart
- ♦ Geotechnical Investigation
- ♦ Applied Geophysical Electrical Methods ( Resistivity Methods )

#### **Hobbies & Interests**

Reading Geology Books, Languages, Udemy Courses, computer, Playing Football, swimming, GYM Workout.